

3F, No. 30, Bainian 2nd St., Longtan Dist., 32560 Taoyuan City, Taiwan

[] (+886) 920-890-202 | ■ emfomy@gmail.com | 🛪 muyang.pro | [] emfomy | 🛡 emfomy | in emfomy

Summary

I currently work as a research assistant at the Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica, advised by Dr. Wei-Yun Ma at the Chinese Knowledge and Information Processing (CKIP) Lab, conducting researches of natural language processing and computational linguistics.

Previously, I received my master degree at Institute of Applied Mathematical Sciences, National Taiwan University, advised by Dr. Weichung Wang, conducting researches of high-performance parallel computing on hybrid CPU-GPU structures.

I have working experience in Thomas J. Watson Research Center, IBM Corporation as an internship, advised by Dr. I-Hsin Chung, conducting researches of high-performance parallel computing on hybrid CPU-GPU structures.

Education

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

M. Sc. in Applied Mathematical Sciences

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2017

• Supervisor: Prof. Weichung Wang

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

B. Sc. in Mathematics

Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2015

Work Experience

VOCATIONAL

CKIP Lab, Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica

Taipei, Taiwan

Jul. 2017 – Present

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Supervisor: Dr. Wei-Yun Ma
- Conducting researches of natural language processing and computational linguistics
 - Knowledge Embedding, Word Embedding
 - Named Entity Linking, Relation Extraction
 - Cluster Management and Maintenance
 - Web/Demo Design and Development

Thomas J. Watson Research Center, IBM Corporation

Yorktown Heights, NY, U.S.A

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2015

- INTERNSHIP
- · Supervisor: Dr. I-Hsin Chung
- Conducting researches of high-performance parallel computing on hybrid CPU-GPU structures

MISCELLANEOUS

Institute of Applied Mathematical Sciences, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Sep. 2013 - Aug. 2017

- · Supervisor: Prof. Weichung Wang
- Conducting researches of high-performance parallel computing on hybrid CPU-GPU structures
 - High-Performance Parallel Computing, Hybrid CPU-GPU Platform
 - Numerical Linear Algebra, Algorithm
 - Cluster Management and Maintenance

Department of Economics, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Taipei, Taiwan 2015 - 2017

Mar. 2016 – Aug. 2016

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Supervisor: Prof. Semin KimConducting researches of ordinal versus cardinal voting rules

National Taiwan University

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Software Development for Computational and Data Science
- Computational Methods and Tools for Data Science
- High Performance Computing and Deep Learning
- Introduction to Computational Mathematics
- Introduction to Scientific Computing
- Numerical Linear Algebra

- Mathematic Software
- Computer Programming (2016)
- Computer Programming (2015)
- Calculus (A)
- Calculus (B)

March 20, 2020 Mu Yang · Résumé Page 1 Of 2

Publications

12th Language Resources and Evaluation Conference (LREC'20)

Marsélle, France

Mu Yang, Chi-Yen Chen, Yi-Hui Lee, Qian-Hui Zeng, Wei-Yun Ma, Chen-Yang Shih, Wei-Jhih Chen

May. 2020

Headword-Oriented Entity Linking: A New Entity Linking Task with Dataset and Baseline

13th IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC'19)

Newport Beach, CA, U.S.A

JHIH-SHENG FAN, MU YANG, PENG-HSUAN LI, WEI-YUN MA

Jan. - Feb. 2019

HWE: Word Embedding with Heterogeneous Features

16th IEEE International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (CIT'16)

Yanuca Island, Fiji

Mu Yang, Ray-Bing Chen, I-Hsin Chung, Weichung Wang

Dec. 2016

Particle Swarm Stepwise Algorithm (PaSS) on Multicore Hybrid CPU-GPU Clusters

Master's Thesis, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Mu Yang, (ADVISOR: WEICHUNG WANG)

Jul. 2017

Highly Scalable Parallelism of Integrated Randomized Singular Value Decomposition with Big Data Applications

Presentation

7th Asian Pacific Congress on Computational Mechanics (APCOM'19)

Taipei, Taiwan

Mu Yang, Dawei Chang, Weichung Wang, Su-Yuen Huang, Ting-Li Chen

Feb. 2019

Parallelized Integration of Multiple Random Sketches from Randomized Singular Value Decomposition with Multi-Level Pairwise Integration Method

9th SIAM Conference on Computational Science and Engineering (SIAM CSE'17)

Atlanta, GA, U.S.A

Mu Yang, Su-Yun Huang, Ting-Li Chen, Weichung Wang

Feb. - Mar. 2017

Parallel Implementations of Integrated Singular Value Decomposition (iSVD)

Selected Projects

CosmEL: Cosmetic Entity Linking

2017 - 2019

A novel entity linking project on cosmetic domain with dataset and baseline. This project is an industrial-academic project with PIXNET Corporation.

HWE: Heterogeneous Word Embedding

2017 - 2018

A general and flexible framework of word embeddings to incorporate each type (e.g. word-sense, part-of-speech, topic) of contextual feature for learning feature-specific word embeddings in an explicit fashion.

iSVD: Integrated Singular Value Decomposition Algorithm

2015 - 2017

A parallel low-rank approximate singular value decomposition solver using integrated randomized algorithm. Implemented for multinode hybrid CPU-GPU systems.

PaSS: Particle Swarm Stepwise Algorithm

2013 - 2015

A parallel stochastic search algorithm for information criterion variable selection problems. Implemented for multinode hybrid CPU-GPU systems.

HiS: Hierarchical Schur Solver

2015 - 2016

A direct linear solver exploiting the sparse structure of multilevel nested dissection matrix to maximize parallel scalability on multinode GPU clusters.

Honors & Awards

Mar. 2019 3rd Place, Formosa Grand Challenge (Chinese TOEFL-like listening comprehension QA)

Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2016 Presentation Excellence, 7th Taiwan-Japan Joint Workshop for Young Scholars in Applied Mathematics

Tainan, Taiwan

Fall 2011 Top 1 Academic Excellence Award, Department of Mathematics, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Skills____

Programming C/C++, Java, Python, Assembly

Libraries MPI/OpenMP, LAPACK/MKL/Magma, CUDA, PyTorch/TensorFlow

Tools Git, CMake, SQL, MATLAB, MTEX
Web Skills JavaScript, Vue, HTML5, CSS, SASS

Languages Chinese, English

March 20, 2020 Mu Yang · Résumé Page 2 0 F 2